<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The case of Richard Fielder, in relation to the petition of the waggoners.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B22947</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99885635</idno>
  <idno type="VID">185480</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240882641</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing F872</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 816.m.14[27]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R224750</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99885635</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99885635e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B22947)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 185480)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C1:3[27])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The case of Richard Fielder, in relation to the petition of the waggoners.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1696]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="personal_name">Fielder, Richard --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Roads --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Political corruption --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  Commerce --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03 </date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-09 </date>
            <label>Simon Charles </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-09 </date>
            <label>Simon Charles</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="statement">
            <pb facs="tcp:185480:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:185480:1"/>
            <head>The <hi>CASE</hi> of <hi>Richard Fielder,</hi> in Relation to the Petition of the <hi>Wag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>goners.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>THE said <hi>Fielder</hi> is Deputy Surveyor of the King's Highways, and by Virtue thereof, constantly attends His Majesty whenever he goes above Ten Miles out of Town.</p>
            <p>That it is his Business to give Notice to all Persons to Repair the High-ways; by reason whereof, several Waggoners on the Roads, finding a Benefit to themselves thereby in their more easy Draughts, have now and then, for the said <hi>Fielder</hi>'s Incouragement, given him Ten Shillings; which they do now pretend, was given by way of Composition, that they might drive with more Horses than the Law allows.</p>
            <p>That since His Majesty's coming to the Throne (which is all the time the said <hi>Fielder</hi> hath been concerned in this Business) he hath been One Year in <hi>Ireland,</hi> and a Year and half imployed in making New Roads in <hi>Hide-Park</hi> and St. <hi>James</hi>'s-<hi>Park,</hi> so that he could not possibly be so much upon the Roads as the said Waggoners pretend (had he no private Concerns of his own which are very great, he being a Corn-Chandler, and imployed in buying Horses for the Army.) And moreover, he hath for Five Years last past, been a Warrant-Servant to His Royal Highness the Prince of <hi>Denmark;</hi> and always in constant waiting whenever the Prince removed his Court, which is well known hath been very often.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Note,</hi> That some of the said Waggoners pretend they have paid the said <hi>Fielder</hi> Five or Ten Shillings <hi>per</hi> Quarter, which is the most: Yet some of them say, That for their own part, they have paid him more than Twenty Pounds, at several times; which is contradictory in it self, for admitting (though by no means granting) that Ten Shillings <hi>per</hi> Quarter were paid, yet in Four Years time according to their own Limitation, the said Summ must fall much short of such their Pretentions.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>That in Case this Honourable House should be of Opinion, That the said</hi> Fielder'<hi>s receiving any Money of the said Waggoners, was for Composition, to let them drive with more Horses than the Law allows (which he does utterly deny, was for any other Reason than what is herein before mentioned) yet he hopes the same is pardoned by the late Act of Grace: For, that it was not, neither could it be proved before the Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nourable Committee, That he has taken One Penny from any of the said Waggoners, within this Year and an half, upon any such Account; and for the Truth thereof, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferrs himself to the Waggoners Evidence, given in before the said Committee, where there is nothing alledged by the Petitioners, of any Quarterly Summ paid him within this Year and an half.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Lastly,</hi> 'Tis greatly to be feared, how Insolent the said Waggoners will be for the future, if they shall receive Incouragement herein: For since their Peti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions have been depending in this Honourable House, they have presumed daily to drive contrary to Law; and particularly one <hi>John Pierce,</hi> drew his Waggon out of the <hi>Swan-Inn</hi> at <hi>Holbourn-Bridge,</hi> on <hi>Saturday</hi> the <hi>29th.</hi> of <hi>February</hi> last, with Nine Horses; and being admonish'd not to do it, he replied, He would do it and see who durst meddle with him. It can be proved, how several of them do now daily drive contrary to, and in Defiance of the Law; and in par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticular <hi>Thomas Child, Thomas Barns,</hi> and <hi>William Whitaker,</hi> who all drove their several and Respective Waggons with Six Horses, at length, to each Waggon, on the Second Instant, in the Parishes of <hi>Bradford, Tilehurst,</hi> and <hi>Reading,</hi> in the County of <hi>Barks,</hi> making their Boasts, That none durst oppose them; besides several others, too long to be mentioned in this Paper. All which is humbly offer'd to your Honours Consideration, by the said <hi>Fielder.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>